Finding Aid for School of Business Administration (University of Michigan) oral history interviews, 1990-1992
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
School of Business Administration (University of Michigan) oral history interviews 1990-1992
University of Michigan. School of Business Administration.
1.5 linear ft. (53 audio cassettes)
03106 Bimu 2
Oral histories of University of Michigan Business School faculty members, conducted by Enid Galler 1976 and 1990-1992, discussing their background, education, careers, and the business school and university.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The oral history interview tapes and transcripts were received from the University of Michigan School of Business Administration (donor no. 6468 ) in January 1999.
The interviews are open for research use.
Oral history project conducted by Enid Galler, 1990-1992 (with one earlier interview dated 1976) to document the history of the University of Michigan School of Business.
The University of Michigan School of Business Administration Oral History Interviews are comprised of typed transcripts and audio cassette tapes of nine interviews with retired faculty members recorded during an oral history project undertaken by the School of Business Administration's Alumni and Development Office. The interviews were conducted by Enid H. Galler between 1990 and 1992 (with one earlier interview identified as being from 1976). The typed transcripts include subject indexes. There are discrepancies between the dates on the transcripts and the dates on the tapes - different dates also appear on the cover sheets of the transcripts and the transcripts themselves. The transcripts and audiotapes are arranged alphabetically by the subject's last name. For consistency, the transcript dates are taken from the cover sheets, and the audiocassette dates are taken from the dates on the cassettes, except in one case where the tape is undated. The date for this cassette tape is taken from the date on the transcript.
Interviews typically include information on the subject's background, education, and family, and commentary on his or her career and overall involvement with the university. The interviews also contain a great deal of information on the administration of, and issues within the School of Business Administration, as well as on the operation of the university as a whole.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. School of Business Administration.; University of Michigan--Faculty.
Contributors:
Bond, Floyd Alden.; Briggs, Robert Peter, 1903-; Bromage, Mary Cogan.; Edwards, Alfred L.; Goodman, Judith; Lim, Linda; McCracken, Paul Winston, 1915-; Miller, Ed; Phelps, Dudley Maynard, 1897-; Pierpont, Wilbur K., 1914-; Pilcher, C. James.; Waterman, Merwin H. (Merwin Howe), 1903-; Wertman, Bert F.; Whitaker, Gilbert R.; White, Joseph B.; Galler, Enid.
Genre Terms:
Oral histories.
- Transcripts
  - Floyd Bond, July 1991 (Box 1)
  - Robert Briggs, August 1990 (Box 1)
  - Mary Bromage, August 1990 (Box 1)
  - Paul McCracken, August 1990 (Box 1)
  - D. Maynard Phelps, August 1990 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur Pierpont, August 1990 (Box 1)
  - C. James Pilcher, July 1991 (Box 1)
  - Merwin H. Waterman, August 1990 (Box 1)
  - Bert F. Wertman, August 1990 (Box 1)
  - B. Joseph White, June 1999 (Box 1)
  - Alfred L. Edwards, July 1999 (Box 1)
  - Judith Goodman, August 1999 (Box 1)
  - Linda Lim, October 1999 (Box 1)
  - Ed Miller, May 1999 (Box 1)
  - Gil R. Whitaker, Jr., September 1999 (Box 1)
  - Interviews-Advisory Committee (Box 1)
- Audiocassettes
  - Floyd Bond, April 1991, 7 tapes (Box 2)
  - Robert Briggs, Fall 1992, 3 tapes (Box 2)
  - Mary Bromage, August 1990, 3 tapes (Box 2)
  - Paul McCracken, Fall 1990, 5 tapes (Box 2)
  - D. Maynard Phelps, November 1989 and January 1990, 4 tapes (Box 2)
  - Wilbur Pierpont, Fall 1990, 5 tapes (Box 2)
  - C. James Pilcher, July 1991, 8 tapes (Box 2)
  - Merwin H. Waterman, undated [Fall 1976], 1 Tape (Box 2)
  - Bert F. Wertman, April 1990, 3 tapes (Box 2)
  - Linda Lim, October 1999, 2 Tapes (Box 2)
  - Judith Goodman, August 1999, 2 Tapes (Box 2)
  - Edwin L. Miller, May 1999, 1 Tape (Box 2)
  - Raymond T. Perring, August 1999, 2 Tapes (Box 2)
  - Gilbert R. Whitaker, Jr., September 1999, 5 Tapes (Box 2)
  - Alfred Edwards, July 1999, 1 Tape (Box 2)
  - Dean B. Joseph White, June 1999, 2 Tapes (Box 2)